LUKKHANA TIPCHAINAK Software Tester/QA

Nakhon Ratchasima, Thailand Mobile: (+66) 91 469 9338 | Email: lukkhanatl@gmail.com github.com/oilly18 | linkedin.com/in/lukkhanatl/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With over 12 years as a Credit Analyst, I bring strong analytical thinking, problem-solving, and attention to detail skills from the banking and finance sectors. Recently, I've developed proficiency in the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) and software testing/QA. Known for my strong communication and collaboration skills, I am eager to leverage my industry expertise, technical skills, and software testing knowledge to enhance software quality and performance in the tech sector.

SKILLS

Technical skills: HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, SQL, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Git/GitHub, Figma, Trello, Postman, Software Testing (manual)

Behavioral skills: Growth Mindset, Teamwork, Time Management, Personal Responsibility, Attention to detail, Problem-Solving, Communication

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer (Bootcamp) (Apr 2024 - Jul 2024) Generation Thailand

- Developed an E-commerce web Application Project following the scrum methodology, divided into front-end using HTML, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, React with React-router and Axios as the main dependency. In the back-end, it uses Node.js and Express to manage the RESTful API and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Developed soft skills such as time management, personal responsibility, attention to detail, problem-solving, growth mindset, communication, persistence, and teamwork.

Credit Analyst (Jan 2012 - Jan 2024)

The Government Savings Bank

- Conducted credit assessments on housing loan and SMEs loan applicants, evaluating financial statements and business plans.
- Analyzed borrower cash flows, profitability, and industry trends to assess repayment capacity, achieving an approval rate of 80%.
- Collaborated closely with the loan officer team to structure loan terms and conditions, ensuring alignment with risk appetite.
- Managed portfolios for 300+ housing loans and 30+ SMEs loans, monitoring repayment performance and conducting reviews.

Branch Officer (Mar 2009 - Mar 2011)

Kasikornbank

- Managed daily cash of 100+ transactions, including deposits, withdrawals, and currency exchange for customers.
- Verified the accuracy of 100+ transactions daily and maintained detailed records to reconcile discrepancies.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with customers, fostering trust and loyalty.

Au Pair (Aug 2006 - Sep 2007)

American Institute For Foreign Study(AIFS), Maryland, U.S.A.

- Provided attentive and nurturing care to children, ensuring their safety, well-being, and development.
- Facilitated cultural exchange by sharing cultural traditions and practices with children and participating in host family activities.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATE

Bachelor Degree in Business Computer (Mar 2003)

Vongchavalitkul University, Nakhon Ratchasima 2nd Class Honors.

Foundations of Software Testing: Manual Testing (May 2024 - Jul 2024)

FutureSkill, Online Certificate

- Enter the world of technology by becoming a QA.
- Basic knowledge for QA and tester.
- Manual testing and various tools for managing tests.
- Workshop on API and Functional Manual Testing.